야, 오늘 땡 잡았다
관리인한테 공짜로 얻었어
We are so in luck!
Treeger said we could have
all this cool stuff!
Wait right there.
기다려
Oh, no. I'm paddling away.
글쎄, 떠내려가는 중이라
진짜? 이 고철덩이를
다 공짜로 얻었다고?
Really? We got all this
rusty crap for free?
This and a bunch of bubble wrap.
And some of it is not even popped.
똑딱 포장비닐도 있는데
안 터뜨린 게 꽤 되더라
Could we be more white trash?
이보다 더 망가질 수 있을까?
The One with the Cuffs
내가 얼마나 절박하게?
How desperate am l?
Good thing Chandler's not here.
He always wins at this game.
챈들러가 있었으면
이 게임 싹 쓸었다
엄마 파티에 요리를
맡는다고 했어
I just told my mom
I'd cater her party.
-How come?
-I need the money.
왜?
돈이 필요하니까
It'd be a great way to get rid of
that last smidgen of self-respect.
쥐알 만한 자존심도
내팽개치고 말았지만
I think this is a good thing.
좋은 일이잖아, 네 실력을
인정하니까 고용한 거 아냐
Mom wouldn't have hired you
if you weren't good.
You don't have to stick up for her.
She can't hear you.
알랑거려봤자
엄마는 오빠 말 못 들어
- 얘들아, 주스 있어?
- 피클뿐이다
Do you have any juice?
Just pickle.
Funny story.
I bumped into Joanna yesterday.
어제 길에서 조애너를
우연히 만났지 뭐겠어
My boss, Joanna?
That must have been awkward.
우리 직장 상사?
좀 불편했겠다
Actually, she asked me
if I wanted a drink.
한잔 하자고 하던데?
You didn't say yes to that,
did you?
설마 승낙하진 않았겠지?
그럼
Hello, Rachel.
안녕, 레이첼
Well, not at first.
처음엔 거절했지
What is she doing here?
여기서 뭐하는 거야?
Last time you went out with her
you said she was a dud!
왜 이래, 전에는
밥맛이라고 했잖아
뭘 몰랐던 거지, 이번엔
한 단계 발전했다니까
I judged her too quickly.
This time, we took it to the next level.
Last time I almost got fired.
You must end it. You must end it now.
나 전에 목 잘릴 뻔했어
지금 당장 끝내
이게 어디 흔한 일이야?
허구헌날 독수공방인데
It's not an everyday occurrence!
Usually I'm in there by myself.
챈들러!
Promise.
약속해...
-Rachel, aren't you running late?
-No
- 레이첼, 안 늦었어?
- 아뇨
-You are if you pick me up a bagel.
-Okay.
- 베이글 챙겨야지
- 알았어요
Promise you will end this now.
끝낸다고 약속해
알았어, 약속하지
끝낼게
-I promise. I'll end it.
-Thank you.
고마워
I hope you know what I'm giving up.
이건 큰 희생이야
단순한 상사가 아니더라
She's not just the boss in your office.
You know what I mean?
무슨 뜻인지 알아?
Sorry.
I knew what he meant.
미안, 난 알거든
How's the hired help?
조수는 잘하고 있니?
Doing great.
Quiches are coming along.
아주 좋아요
파이는 끝나가요
이건 뭐야
푸른색 매니큐어니?
What's this?
Blue nail polish?
I thought it was cute.
네, 예쁘잖아요
It's what your grandmother's hands
looked like when we found her.
돌아가신 할머니 찾았을 때
손톱이 꼭 이랬어
Let me ask you a question.
궁금한 게 있는데
Why did you hire me?
왜 절 쓰셨어요?
리처드가 네 음식에
정신을 못 차렸잖니
Richard raved about
the food at his party...
...but you were sleeping with him.
물론 너랑 잔 사이지만
Then I heard the food at that
lesbian wedding was nice.
그 레즈비언 결혼식 때
요리도 좋았다면서
I assume you didn't sleep
with anyone there.
걔들하고는 안 잤겠지만
At least that would be something.
그럼 믿을 만하잖니
Oh, my God!
Did you hear that?
세상에, 들었니?
She hired me because
she thinks I'm good.
내 실력을 보고 쓴 거래
I didn't hear that.
그런 말은 없었잖아
동정심 때문도 아니고
She didn't hire me out of pity.
It wasn't so she could pick on me.
She actually thinks I'm good.
괴롭히려는 것도 아니고
내 솜씨를 믿어준 거야
너 레즈비언이라도 괜찮아
And hey, it's cool
if you're a lesbian.
Good afternoon. Are you
the decision-maker of the house?
안녕하세요
이 집의 가장이십니까?
Do you currently own
a set of encyclopedias?
혹시 백과사전
갖고 계신가요?
No, but try the classifieds.
People sell everything in there.
아뇨, 신문광고를 보면
좋은 게 있을 겁니다
Actually, I'm not buying.
I'm selling.
사는 게 아니라
팔려는 겁니다
Let me ask you one question.
질문 하나 드리죠
Do your friends ever have
a conversation...
친구 분들 대화를 듣고
...and you just nod along,
not sure what they're talking about?
영문도 모른 채 고개를
끄덕인 적은 없나요?
I'm telling you,
it's totally unconstitutional.
- 이건 명백한 위헌이야
- 그럼, 당연하지
I think he deserves a Nobel Prize.
- 노벨상을 받아야 돼
- 무슨 소리!
It was like the
Algonquin kids' table.
완전 알곤킨족 테이블이네
Excuse me. I'm sorry.
실례지만 2분 30초 동안
아무 말도 없으신데
You haven't said anything
for about two minutes.
그렇게 구미가 당깁니까?
Are you at all interested?
네, 그럼요
입장하시죠
Come on in.
-That's weird.
-What?
이상하다
- 뭐가?
- 네 손톱
Your nails.
엄마가 손톱 물어뜯는다고 하도
잔소릴 해서 가짜를 붙이고 왔어
I wore fake ones so my mom wouldn't
give me grief about biting them.
그게 아니라
아홉 개밖에 없잖아
I meant, it's weird that
you only have nine now.
Oh, my God!
맙소사
Wait a minute.
잠깐, 아까 그게...
I had them when I put
Oh, my God!
It's in the quiche!
파이에 들어갔어!
- 일 났네
- 걱정 마
-Oh, my God!
-Okay, don't panic.
I'll go buy you a new set of nails.
내가 금방 가게에 가서 손톱을
사올 테니까, 아무도 모를 거야
No one will know,
and you'll look great!
It's because they're going to eat
That's the problem.
이런... 파이에
들어간 게 문제구나
Honey, don't bite your nails.
손톱 깨물지 마라
놀라지 마세요
Please don't freak out.
There's a blue fingernail
in one of the quiche cups.
파이에 손톱이 들어갔어요
And there's no way to know which one.
어떤 건지는 모르지만
And whoever finds it wins the prize!
찾는 사람이 당첨되는 거죠
I'm not freaking out.
놀라지 않았다
-Why are you laughing?
-Now your father owes me $5.
왜 웃으세요?
아빠한테 5달러
받을 일이 생겨서
You bet I'd lose a nail?
손톱 빠지는 데 거셨어요?
Don't be silly.
I just bet that I'd need these.
무슨 소리,
이걸 준비하자고 했거든
Frozen lasagnas?
냉동 라자냐?
You bet that I'd screw up?
이렇게 될 줄 아셨어요?
All that stuff about how I was good
절 믿는다는 얘기는...
아니, 그건 사실이다
본성만 드러내지 않으면
No, that was all true.
This was just in case
you "pulled a Monica."
You promised Dr. Weinberg
you'd never use that phrase.
와인버그 박사님과 그 말은
안 하기로 약속하셨잖아요
Come on.
Have a sense of humor.
왜 이러니, 가끔은 자기를
보고 웃을 줄도 알아야지
You're never able to
laugh at yourself.
That's right.
맞아요
My mom has no faith in me!
That's hilarious!
엄마는 날 안 믿는다
너무 웃기지?
안 웃긴데?
I don't get it.
No. I have faith.
아냐, 널 믿는다
라자냐를 믿겠죠
No. You have lasagnas!
The ruined quiches are ready!
몹쓸 파이가 다 익었네?
-I really don't think we should be doing this.
-Okay.
- 우리 이럼 안돼요
- 알았어
It just doesn't feel like
we're breaking up.
헤어지는 느낌이 안 나는데
No, we are.
I'm sad.
아니, 맞아
무지 슬퍼
좋아요
네
Can you wait till tomorrow?
All right.
내일은 안 될까요?
그러죠
까무러치겠네
Unbelievable!
고마워요
Thanks.
That was my boss.
I have to go.
아니, 사장님이야
가야겠어
네
What are you doing?
뭐해?
-I'm getting dressed.
-Why?
옷 입으려고
왜?
When I walk outside naked,
people throw garbage.
이대로 나가면 사람들이
쓰레기를 던질 테니까
Wait.
I want to show you something.
기다려
보여줄 게 있어
What is it?
뭐죠?
Just a little gag gift
somebody gave me.
선물로 받은 노리개
Put your hands together.
손을 한데 모아
You're not the boss of me.
당신은 내 상사가 아닌데
Yeah, you are.
네, 맞아요
Saucy!
벌써 아찔해
I'll be back in two minutes.
2분 후에 올게
You're going to leave me like this?
이대로 두고 간다고?
Knowing you're here waiting for me.
I think it's exciting, don't you?
자기가 여기서 날 기다린다?
생각만 해도 짜릿해
하지만 빨리 안 돌아오면...
If you don't come back soon...
...there's pretty much
nothing I can do about it!
대책 없다는 것만 알아둬요
I brought you back a macaroon.
마카롱 좀 드세요
그래, 자기 코랑 같이
엉덩이에 콕 끼워둘게
Great. I'll keep it in
my butt with your nose.
That's weird.
She locked the door.
왜 문을 잠갔지?
You know why? She's got
the bonus list in there.
성탄절 상여금 명단이 있거든
오늘 아침에 작성했어
I saw her working on it today.
Swear you won't tell.
좋아, 말하지 마
마크가 키를 맡기고 갔어
When Mark left, he gave me
a key to her office.
You want to see the list?
- 보고 싶지?
- 그럼!
안녕?
How are you?
반가워요
네, 조애너...
Hello, Joanna
office.
...의 사무실입니다
I'm sorry.
I'll be a little longer.
미안한데 시간이 좀 걸리겠어
-How little?
-A couple hours.
얼마나요?
한두 시간 더
나도 힘들어
This isn't funny.
Get back here now!
재미없으니까
당장 돌아와요
-I can't!
-Why not?
- 안돼!
- 왜요?
I'm in my boss' car.
사장님 차 안이야
-What?
-Tunnel!
- 뭐요?
- 어? 터널이네
What?
뭐!
Rachel, could I see you
for a moment?
레이첼, 잠깐 나 좀 볼까?
Okay, here's the situation.
현재상황은 이래
The keys to the cuffs
are on the door.
수갑 키는 문 뒤에 있거든?
Could you be a doll...
잽싸게 들고 와서
풀어주면 고맙겠어
...and grab them and
scoot on over here and unlock me?
And on a totally separate subject,
that's a lovely pantsuit.
상관없는 주제지만
그 옷 참 예쁘다
You promised you would
break up with her.
헤어진다고 약속했지?
I did break up with her!
She just took it really, really well!
헤어지려고 했는데
너무 고분고분하잖아
내 밥줄 떨어진다는
생각은 안 들었어?
Jeopardizing my career
never entered your mind?
It did enter my mind.
들긴 들었는데
일이 요상하게 꼬여서...
But then something happened
that made it shoot right out.
까먹었지 뭐
You got yourself into those cuffs,
you get yourself out.
네가 자초한 일이니까
알아서 해결해
안돼, 이걸 어떻게 풀어
I can't get myself right out of them.
마술사 챈들러랑
헷갈리지 마
You must have me confused with
the "Amazing Chandler"!
Unlock me! She could be gone
for hours, and I'm cold and....
어서 풀어줘, 한참 있어야
올 거야, 무지 추워...
챈들러, 최후통고야
다시는 만나지 마!
All right! This is it!
Never see her again.
Never!
그럼
- 이 사무실에도 오면 안돼
- 물론
-Never come in here again.
-Fine!
내 워크맨 돌려주고
Give me back my Walkman!
난... 워크맨 빌린 적 없는데?
I never borrowed it.
Then I lost it.
Buy me one!
잃어버렸군
하나 사줘!
You got it! Here we go!
Come on. This is great!
알았어, 어서
이제 살았다
Does it hurt?
아프냐?
No, I always see guys do this
when handcuffs are taken off.
아니, 영화에선 꼭 이러더라
Hello, sweet pants!
어여쁜 내 바지!
Wait!
What will you tell Joanna?
잠깐! 조애너한테
뭐라고 하지?
About what?
뭘?
She'll see you're gone and know
I let you out, and I'll get fired!
내가 풀어준 걸 알면
그 자리에서 해고야
난 거짓말 잘하니까 걱정 마
사실 워크맨 빌렸거든
I'll tell a lie!
I'm good at lying!
I actually did borrow your Walkman!
She'll know I have
a key to her office.
나한테 방 키가 있잖아
다시 수갑 채워야겠다
I've got to lock you back up.
I don't think so.
고렇겐 못해
This is much better.
훨씬 낫다
Here's somebody interesting.
이게 재미있겠군요
반 고흐를 아시죠?
What do you know about Van Gogh?
귀를 자른 사람
-He cut off his ear.
-And?
그리고?
I'm out.
포기
He painted that.
이걸 그렸어요
That's pretty nice.
근사하네요, 머저리라서
귀를 자른 게 아니었군요
I thought he cut off his ear
because he sucked.
또 뭐가 있죠?
-What else you got in there?
-Let's see....
어디 보자...
-Where does the Pope live?
-ln the woods.
- 교황은 어디 살죠?
- 숲에
잠깐, 그건 우스갯소리고
Wait, that's the joke answer.
Actually, it's Vatican City.
바티칸시티예요
경화고무의 용도는?
Now, what do you know about
vulcanized rubber?
Spock's birth control.
스파크의 피임기구
You need these books.
선생은 이 책이 필요해요
This used to be your room?
이게 네 방이었니?
You must have been in
really good shape as a kid.
와, 어렸을 때
몸매 좋았겠다
I'm such an idiot!
내가 바보였어
엄마가 변할 줄 알았다니
I can't believe I thought
she could change.
Who cares what your mom thinks?
엄마 생각이 뭐가 중요해
본성을 드러낸 것뿐인데
So you "pulled a Monica."
이해했다니 기쁘다
I'm glad that's catching on.
Why does that have to be a bad thing?
Just change what it means.
좋은 뜻으로 바꾸면 되잖아
엄마가 틀렸다는 걸 증명해
Prove your mother wrong.
You finish the job, and
we'll call that "pulling a Monica."
맡은 일을 끝내는 게
모니카의 본성이니까
What?
뭐?
줄줄이 A만 맞는 아이도
모니카의 본성
If a kid gets straight A's, his
parents say, "You pulled a Monica."
A fireman saves a baby,
and they go, "He pulled a Monica."
아기를 구한 소방관도
모니카의 본성
장외홈런이 터지면
관중들이 열광하지
Someone hits a homer, and they say,
"That one's out of here."
Because some things don't change.
안 변하는 것도 있으니까
All right.
I'll go down there.
그래, 내려갈게
I won't serve the lasagna.
I'll serve what I make.
라자냐가 아니라
내 요리를 낼 거야
My breasts are really strong.
내 가슴 진짜 세다
챈들러, 아까처럼 있어
내 일자리가 걸렸다고
I have to get you locked back up.
I'm so going to lose my job!
여긴 아무도 못 들어와
이제야 이유를 알겠네
She's very private about her office!
Now I know why!
어쨌든 일은 터졌어
You're in trouble either way.
들어와서 지금 이 꼴을 보면
다 알게 되니까 그냥 풀어줘
If she sees me locked to this...
...she'll know you were here.
You might as well let me go.
-I'll clean your bathroom for a month.
-Still won't be clean.
- 한 달 간 욕실 청소
- 닦아봤자 소용없어
All I want is my freedom.
내가 원하는 건 자유야
-Foot rubs for a month!
-Freedom!
- 발 마사지 한 달
- 자유!
-I'll put all your photos into albums!
-I want my freedom!
앨범 정리도 해줄게
난 자유를 원해!
모르겠어? 사람 살려!
Why won't you hear me!
Sophie, help me!
Sophie, sit!
소피, 앉아!
흥분하지 마
Would you just calm down?!
I'm going to say this
for the last time.
마지막으로 얘기할게
Would you please just
좋은 말로 할 때...
There's a lot I didn't know
about vomit.
구토의 원인이
이렇게 다양할 줄이야
In a minute.
금방 간다
So what do you say?
어떻습니까, 백과사전
전질에 1,200달러면
You get the whole set
of encyclopedias for $1200.
That works out to
just 50 bucks a book.
권당 겨우 50달러죠
$1200?
1,200달러?
You think I have $1200?
제게 그런 돈이 있을까요?
I'm home during the day...
거실에 고철가구를 들이고
대낮에 집이나 보는 녀석이?
...and I got patio furniture
in my living room.
There's a few things
you don't get from book learning.
책에는 이런 거 안 나왔죠?
Well, what can you swing?
교환할 것도 없나요?
How about zero down and zero a month
for a long, long time?
무일푼에 알거지가
바로 이런 경우죠
You don't have anything?
아무 것도 없습니까?
You want to see what I got?
보여드려요?
좋습니다
I got a baby Tootsie Roll...
막대사탕, 영화티켓
열쇠, 클리넥스
...a movie stub, keys, a Kleenex...
...a rock...
바위, 그리고 군인
안녕?
...and an army man.
Okay, I get the picture.
Thanks for your time.
네, 알겠습니다
어쨌든 고맙군요
And a fifty.
그리고 50달러!
챈들러 바지인가?
These must be Chandler's pants.
한 권은 살 수 있겠군요
For $50 you can get one book.
What will it be?
A? B? C?
뭘로 하실까요?
I'll stick with the V.
V가 좋겠어요
놈의 정체가 궁금하니까
I want to see how
this bad boy turns out.
I will buy and wrap
all of your Christmas gifts!
- 성탄절 선물을 다 사주면?
- 안돼!
I'll squeeze you fresh orange juice
every morning!
아침마다 오렌지주스 짜줄게
-With extra pulp?
-Yeah.
- 걸쭉하게?
- 그럼!
싫어
I've got it!
알았다
You don't have it.
너한테 없을 걸?
I have so got it!
바로 그거야
There will be rumors about this.
No way to stop it.
이 소문이 짜하게 퍼지고 있어
소피랑 모니카, 피비 다 알아
Sophie, Monica and Phoebe know.
-How do they know?
-I called them.
- 모니카랑 피비가 어떻게...
- 내가 전화했어
When they ask me what I saw...
걔들이 물어보면
부드럽게 얘기해줄까?
...I can be very generous...
...or very stingy.
적나라하게 까발릴까?
Go on.
계속해봐
I can make you a legend.
널 전설로 만들어주지
I can make you
this generation's Milton Berle.
이 시대의 밀튼 벌이
되는 거야
-And Milton Berle has
-Not compared to you.
- 그 밀튼 벌이...
- 너랑은 쨉이 안 되지
- 라자냐는 손도 안 대
- 진짜?
They're not even
touching the lasagna.
- 네 전골 인기폭발이다
- 그렇지!
They love your casserole!
It's hard to believe a while
ago this was just ingredients.
몇 분 전만 해도
날 재료였는데
Everyone seems to like your dish.
다들 네 요리를 좋아하는구나
And you?
엄마는?
I thought it was...
내 입맛에도...
...quite tasty.
딱 맞더라
So if everyone liked it,
and you liked it...
다른 사람도 좋았고
엄마도 좋았다면 성공이네요
...that would make this a success.
Which would make you....
- 그럼 엄마는...
- 마귀할멈?
A bitch?
I meant "wrong,"
but we can use your word.
꼭 그런 건 아니지만
굳이 표현하자면 뭐
Yes, well, I was wrong.
그래, 엄마가 틀렸다
오늘 정말...
And I have to say...
...you really impressed me today.
감동 먹었다
You might even say that she
"pulled a Monica."
본성을 드러낸 거죠
She doesn't know we switched it.
바뀐 거 모르시지?
And the next time you cater for me...
다음에 이런 기회가 있으면
냉동실에 얼음만 넣어두마
...there will be nothing but ice
in the freezer.
That really means a lot.
그래주신다면야
엄마, 손톱 깨물지 마세요
Mom, don't bite your nails!
안녕
왔어?
Hello, Chandler.
챈들러 왔구나
I love you.
사랑한다
왜 그래?
What's going on?
No, he doesn't!
그럴 리가
Two hours, that lasted.
두 시간 만에 끝났군
So did you break up with Joanna?
- 조애너랑 헤어졌지?
- 그런 거 같아
I think so.
베수비오처럼 폭발하기 전에
끝내길 잘했지
It's good you got out,
before she blew up like Vesuvius.
The volcano?
그 화산?
그래, 말이 났으니 말인데
정말 대단한 화성암층이지?
Speaking of volcanoes, man, are they
a violent igneous rock formation!
What?
뭐?
Lava spewing, hot ash.
뜨거운 용암과 화산재
물론 휴화산도 있지만
Of course, some are dormant.
Why are you talking about volcanoes
all of a sudden?
갑자기 화산이 왜 나와?
그럼 무슨 얘기할까
뭐가 좋아? 생체해부?
We don't have to.
What do you want to talk about?
Vivisection?
The vas deferens?
수정관?
The Vietnam War?
월남전?
Did anyone see that documentary
on the Korean War?
한국전쟁 다큐멘터리
본 사람 있어?
그래
너무 아름다운 나라야
Korea's a beautiful country.
그 한 많은 역사...
With such a sad history.
Could there be more Kims?
진짜 김씨 많더라
- 밖에 누구야?
- 저예요, 안녕하세요
-Who's out there?
-Me! Good morning!
Could you come in here, please?
레이첼, 잠깐 들어올래?
Sure! They didn't have
poppyseed bagels...
네, 그러죠
양귀비씨 베이글이 없어서
참깨로 가져왔는데, 저런...
...so I have sesame
Oh, my word!
I've had a slight office mishap.
경미한 사고가 생겼거든
Could you get the key for me?
문 뒤에 키가 있어
네, 알았어요
이런 일이...
죄송
-lf you could.
-Oh, I'm sorry!
- 지금 나랑...
- 죄송해요!
You can tell your friend Chandler
we're definitely broken up this time!
챈들러한테 이젠 진짜
끝장이라고 전해